# Bahadır Gökdemir

**L** Phone number: (+90) 05442736559 **■ Email address:** <u>bahadirgokdemir@hotmail.com</u>

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bahadır-gökdemir-160b981b3/

**Website:** <a href="https://github.com/bahadirgokdemir">https://github.com/bahadirgokdemir</a>

• Home: Ertuğrulgazi Mahallesi Şen sokak No:4/6 Çankaya/ANKARA, 06530 Ankara (Türkiye)

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a dedicated Software and Systems Engineer with experience in Linux systems, VPN architecture, and network security. My experience spans a variety of development and security roles, from building efficient systems applications in C# to back-end development with Django and Flask. I am developing myself virtual networking, high availability deployments, and open source firewall solutions. With a solid foundation in Linux, Docker, and IPsec VPNs, I am committed to delivering secure, high-performance solutions in challenging environments.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software and System Engineer**

**Labris Networks** [ 01/10/2023 – Current ]

City: Ankara | Country: Türkiye

- Worked with Linux interfaces for virtual networking, IPsec VPN and firewall development using C, C++ and Python.
- Experienced in problem detection and log analysis on Linux operating systems.
- Experienced in configuring high availability and backup systems, SD-WAN and IDS-IPS.
- Implemented tunneling with WireGuard, PPTP and L2TP over IPsec.
- Established Nginx server configurations, logging and reporting frameworks.
- Developed daemon services with Django and Flask for Unix systems and backend applications using PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite and Redis.
- Experienced in OOP, multi-threading and multi-processing techniques for efficient and scalable solutions.

# **Cyber Security Intern**

**Labris Networks** [ 14/08/2023 – 30/09/2023 ]

City: Ankara | Country: Türkiye

- Conducted PPTP tunneling using Strongswan.
- Configured packet filtering on Docker topologies with OpenVSwitch and XDP.
- Managed and monitored various backend structures developed with Django, deployed across multiple ports using Nginx and Docker to meet user requirements.
- Gained experience with TLS 1.2 and 1.3 protocols for enhanced security.

### **Software Developer**

**Gazi Üni. Bilişim Enstitüsü** [ 20/10/2022 – 15/07/2023 ]

City: Ankara | Country: Türkiye

• I developed secure, closed-system applications in C#, including an algorithm to optimize exam schedules and contributed to building a LAN-based application managed on a Windows Server for authorized officer access.

### **Hardware and network Intern**

**Savtim AŞ.** [ 10/09/2024 – 16/10/2024 ]

City: Ankara | Country: Türkiye

- Had the opportunity to observe the construction stages of router and switch devices.
- Gained experience in configuring DHCP and NAT.
- Worked extensively on LAN systems, gaining foundational knowledge of network setup and operations.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **Computer Engineering**

**Gazi University** [ 14/09/2020 – Current ]

# **High School Education**

Bahcesehir College Unye [ 29/06/2020 ]

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Turkish

Other language(s):

# **English**

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

c# / c / html / Java / OOP (Object Oriented Programming / Devops: Docker, Jenkins / Web server Apache/ Nginx / OpenVSwitch / VPN Architecture: Wireguard, OpenVPN, tinc, L2TP+IPSEC, IKEv2, PPTP / MySQL, SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL / Caching Backend: Redis / python / Web Application Firewall / Backend Development: Python (Django)

# **PROJECTS**

[ 13/10/2022 - 05/06/2023 ]

### **Log Analysis Application**

This project focuses on analyzing logs from various devices, such as PaloAlto, Fortinet, and Harpp, and converting them into a readable format. Developed using Java, the application can parse and analyze different types of logs. Logs are manually input into the system, and the analyzed results are compiled into comprehensive reports.

[ 14/07/2023 - 03/09/2023 ]

### **Package Filter**

This project uses OpenVswitch, Docker, and XDP technologies to filter and drop specific packets based on user-defined keywords. It allows users to target and remove certain types of network traffic efficiently.

[ 10/09/2024 - Current ]

### Artificial intelligence based attack detection and prevention system

The Artificial Intelligence-Based Intrusion Detection and Prevention System aims to detect and prevent cyber attacks as close to real-time as possible using machine learning and adapts to new threats to increase network security.

### **VOLUNTEERING**

Gazi Üniversitesi Yapay Zeka Topluluğu

# **Sponsorship Coordinator**

To establish cooperation on all kinds of activities of the community